Yogesh Mithoon

Interaction Design | User Experience

The reason why I chose this career path is that as a UI/UX and Product designer is because I have a chance to shape services and new digital products even from scratch, co-creating with clients, targeted users and our team. It means tons of voices, motives, and reasons to require under consideration . It's a true rollercoaster of working with different experiences.

Experience

UI/UX designer at goplaybook

Feb 2019 - Jun 2019

Worked alongise a team of 3 for a startup called goplaybook. Was responsible for Prototyping and Design Testing.

Freelance UI/UX and Graphic Designer

Sept 2017 - Present

Worked for multiple startups in many fields such as Interaction, Branding, Graphic and Logo Design. Worked as Senior Designer and Design head for college fests and also held the key responsiblity in developing the college fest website.

Education

Self Taught UI/UX Designer.

Courses in Interaction Design Foundation, Udemy. Certifications Included

B.Tech, Mechanical Engineering. (Drop Out)

July 2016 - Apr 2020

National Institute of Technology, Calicut.

+91 7994322116

yogeshmithoon.com

yogeshmithoon@gmail.com

Skills

Sketching, Wireframing,

UI Design, Interaction Design,

Responsive Web Design,

Rapid Prototyping

Programming

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript,

Python

Tools

Photoshop, AdobeXD, Figma

Illustrator, Invision Studio

UXPin, Marvel, Cinema 4D

Selected Projects

Feel -Smartwatch for the Deafblind

Designed a Smartwatch that would help the deafblind people to communicate via messaging. Other features in this product design include - Alarm, Emergency Contact and Time. Solely responsible for the Research and Design of this product

Swishh - Basketball Community and Scoring App

Designed an App that connects basketball players and helps them conduct games and tournaments. Also includes the UX of scoring the basketball games. Solely responsible for Research and Design.

Zoomcar - Redesign.

This is a redesign project I did as a UI/UX exercise for 2 weeks. This helped me improvise my UX research techniques and my design thinking methods along with my designing skills. Followed design thinking in this redesign process.

Swishh - Basketball Community and Scoring App

Designed an App that connects basketball players and helps them conduct games and tournaments. Also includes the UX of scoring the basketball games. Solely responsible for Research and Design.